### Contact

281-513-1264 (Work) aamckinn@texaschildrens.org

www.linkedin.com/in/adrian-mckinney-b034a895 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing
Public Health Nursing
Community Outreach

Certifications

RNC-LRN--Low Risk Neonatal

#### Honors-Awards

Gold Medal - Excellence in Nursing

Excellence in Nursing--Bronze Award Winner

Houston Chronicle's Top 100 Nurses in Houston

Nursing Excellence Award--"Team of the Year" 2015

Nurse of the Year

# Adrian McKinney

Nurse Manager at Texas Children's Health Plan--Nurse Family Partnership

Houston, Texas Area

# Summary

Experienced Nurse Leader with a demonstrated history of success working in the hospital, community, non-profit health care industry, and with grant funded programs. Believes in doing what's right, not what's easy, even when nobody's looking. Skilled in Leadership, Motivational Interviewing, Case Management, Healthcare, Research, and Patient Safety. Strong professional with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Nursing from The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston. Consistently exceptional performance.

# Experience

Texas Children's Health Plan--Nurse Family Partnership 30 years

Nurse Manager September 2008 - Present (11 years 11 months)

6330 West Loop South Suite 1280 Bellaire, Texas 77401

Responsible for management and oversight of the Nurse Family Partnership Program (NFP). The NFP program is a home visitation program that pairs a Bachelor's prepared Registered Nurse with a first-time, low-income mother for 2.5 years. Original supervisor at this site since the program's inception in 2008. Responsible for the creation of all program materials, budget, policy, hiring, state reporting, training, quality improvement, marketing, outreach, legislative education and supervision of all staff.

Nurse Manager and Staff RN August 1990 - September 2008 (18 years 2 months) Medical Center- Fannin

Dayshift Manager--January 2005- September 2008 -- 62 bed level 2+ NICU responsible for hiring, staffing, schedules, performance reviews, special projects, on-call coverage, staff meetings, administrative issues, and committee chair for various committees.

From 1990-1998-- Staff nurse on dayshift in the Infant Care II-NICU. Expanded roles included: Charge Nurse, Preceptor, Level II Transport nurse, and various committees. Responsible for all aspects of care for the sick, surgical, or premature infant (up to 4 patients a shift).

Staff Nurse, Charge Nurse, Interim Manager June 1998 - January 2005 (6 years 8 months) Texas Medical Center- Houston

Telephone Triage position. Fielding calls from 110 Physician's and the ER. Assessment, Triage, Education, Emergency referrals, Home Care advice and Rx management. Quality monitoring, billing, statistics, and Retention Committee.

## Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing · (1988 - 1990)